喂
Hey.
不會有事的
It's going to be okay.
只要告訴我 我們做的是正確的事
Just tell me we're doing the right thing.
不 親愛的 我知道你想去修補
No, sweetheart, I know you want to fix this.
這是你的本行 可我們盡力了
It's what you do. But we've tried.
好嗎 我們盡力了 可看看結果是什麼
All right? We've been trying and look where it's gotten us.
我覺得分開一段時間對他有好處
And I think the space is gonna be good for him.
對我們都好 而且 這是所好學校
For all of us. Besides, it's a good school.
等夏天一過他就回家了
He'll be home by the end of the summer.
是啊
Yeah.
我不會有事的 我保證
I'll be okay. I promise.
我保證
I promise.
我愛你
Love you.
我也愛你
Love you, too.
給我打電話
Call me.
我會的
Will do.
我愛你
I love you.
哇
Wow.
好樣的 史蒂芬
Well done, Stephen.
太棒了
Amazing!
住手 媽媽
Oh, stop, Mom!
那是什麼 那是什麼
What's that? What's that?
什麼
Huh? Oh!
一 二 三
One, two, three!
漂亮
Nice.
耶
Yeah!
它基本死了
He's pretty dead.
它死定了
He's very dead.
今天 我兒子成了大人
Today my son has become a man.
為此
Because of that...
我知道你覺得 我們這麼做是為了懲罰你
I know you think we're probably doing this to punish you,
可我們不是
but we're not.
好嗎
All right?
我和你媽是為你好
Your mother and I want the best for you.
你根本不知道她想要什麼
You have no idea what she wants.
我不知道你為何這麼做
I don't know why you're doing this.
是你被學校開除的
I'm not the one that got expelled, pal.
她不想趕走我 是你想
Well, she doesn't want me gone. It's you.
不是的 史蒂芬
That's not true, Stephen.
就是的 你要把我送走
Yes, it is. You're sending me away.
不是的 史蒂芬
It's not true, Stephen.
我和你媽經過長時間的商量
Your mother and I had a long conversation...
商量什麼
About what?
我們需要緩一緩
We need a break, Stephen!
我不想緩一緩
I don't want a break! All right?
閉嘴 我恨你
Both of us, okay? Shut up! I hate you!
你冷靜
Just calm down. Calm down!
不別碰我
No, don't touch me!
別碰我
Don't touch me!
你冷靜
You just calm down!
別碰我
Don't touch me!
冷靜
Calm down!
譯名: 禁閉 / 冰鎮房嚇(港) / 育陰房(台)
醒醒 醒醒
Wakey, wakey.
起床了
Rise and shine.
你準備好鍛煉了嗎
You ready for your workout?
張開嘴
Open.
很可能整個新英格蘭地區的暴雪
...significant snowfall likely across all of New England,
總之就是這樣
when all is said and done.
隨著暴風雪的臨近
So, as the storm approaches,
你要確定採取了必要的預防措施
you'll want to make sure you take the necessary precautions here
準備好你的所在地會有重大降雪
and plan on some very heavy snow in your area for much of...
輪到你了
It's your turn.
要不要試試看
How about a quick try?
好樣的
Great job.
嗨
Hey.
我想繼續再給他治療幾周
So I'd like to continue working with him for another couple weeks.
這不是我的決定
It's not my decision.
他們要送他去波士頓
They're moving him to Boston.
一個聾啞兒童的福利院
Some group home for deaf kids.
可我們在取得進步
But we're making progress.
這些事需要時間
These things take time.
他是個好孩子 我們可以
He's a great kid, we can...
他上周又打斷了一個孩子的胳膊
He broke another kid's arm last week.
他不能留在斯威策
He can't stay at Sweetser.
我很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我們要走了
We're leaving.
瓊
Joan!
等一下
Wait a second.
我覺得就像
I guess it was like a...
我覺得就像所有聰明人的證書
I guess it was like certificates for all the smart people,
所以我基本什麼都沒
so basically I have nothing.
我 我沒有
I... I did not...
我想送給你
I want you to have these.
別凍著 好嗎
Keep warm, okay?
你不可能照顧緬因州所有的孩子瑪麗
Well, you can't take care of every kid in Maine, Mary.
我知道
I know.
呃
Um...
沒人會因為你需要幫助而瞧不起你
No one would judge you for needing help.
謝謝
Thanks.
嗨 威爾森醫生
Hi, Dr. Wilson.
你怎麼樣 還好嗎
How are you? How's it all going?
漫長的一天
Long day.
漫長的一周
Long week.
蒂芬一直讓你分不開身 是不是
Well, Stephen really keeps you on your toes, doesn't he?
他還好嗎
How's he doing?
我收到了文件
I received the papers.
我要把他送到卡文頓
I'm moving him to Covington.
在身體上 我能照顧他
Physically, I can manage.
基本沒問題
Just about,
但這不是他
but it's not him.
只是個我餵飯 擦洗 穿衣的一具肉體
It's just a body that I feed, and wash, and clothe.
在我失去理查德的那一天 我也失去了他
I lost him that day I lost Richard in the car.
瑪麗 身為心理醫生 不等於就是好父母
Mary, being a psychologist doesn't make you a perfect parent.
沒這樣的事
There's no such thing.
你做了你認為是正確的
You did what you thought was right.
我把他送走了
I sent him away.
我把兒子送走了 現在他沒了
I sent my son away and now he's gone.
媽媽會給你買一隻模仿鳥
Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird
如果這只模仿鳥不唱歌
And if that mockingbird don't sing
媽媽會給你
Mama's gonna buy you
買個鑽戒
A diamond ring
報警台 你有什麼情況
911, what's your emergency?
喂
Hello?
我是瑪麗·波特曼
Yes, this is Mary Portman
住在德爾福路28號
from 28 Delphi Lane.
我家裏好像進來了人
I think there is an intruder in my house.
好 別掛電話
Okay, stay on the line.
波特曼夫人 你在房子裏嗎
Mrs. Portman, are you inside the house?
能聽到我嗎
Can you hear me?
波特曼夫人你還在嗎
Mrs. Portman, are you still there?
喂
Hello?
對不起 我的錯
I'm sorry, my mistake.
只是一隻浣熊
It's just a raccoon.
給 喝了能暖和
Here you go. This will warm you up.
你沒事吧
You okay?
等等 喂
Oh. Hold on. Hello?
瓊 嗨 謝謝 你回電話
Joan, hi. Thanks for calling back.
對不起 我知道現在很晚了
I'm sorry, I know it's late.
他怎麼到這裏的 外面零下9度
How did he even get here? It's 15 degrees out.
這我知道 但是拜託 瓊
I know it's not, but please, Joan.
我可以幫他
I can help him.
他可以住在這裏
He could just stay here.
等一下 有這個必要嗎
Hang on a second. Is that necessary?
讓我 給個機會吧
What? Let me... Give it a chance, okay?
我可以幫他
I can help him.
報警有什麼用處
What good could it do to involve the police?
我願意承擔這個風險
I'll take that chance.
他才九歲 瓊 拜託
He's nine years old, for God's sake, Joan, please!
你能不能讓他
Can you just let him...
瓊 我等會再打給你
Joan, I'll call you back.
湯姆
Tom!
天啊
Jesus.
湯姆
Tom!
你回去之前不再喝一杯嗎 喬
You sure I can't get you another before you head back out, Joe?
謝謝你 瑪麗 我要抓緊時間
Thanks, Mary. I'm gonna press on,
開始挨家挨戶打聽
start going door to door.
這種低溫 一個小孩子在外面不會活很久
A young kid out alone won't survive long in these temperatures.
在他們的公司網站上
...though on their company website
銷售額和轉化率要高得多
have much higher sales numbers and conversion rates.
我感覺很無助
I just feel so helpless.
是啊 我
Yeah, I...
我一下午都在外面找他
I've been out all afternoon looking for him myself.
天啊 瓊
Oh, God, Joan.
不敢想像他一個人在外面會是什麼樣子
I can't stand to think of him out there on his own.
好 呃
Yeah, okay, um...
向我保證一有消息就給我打電話
Well, just promise me you'll call as soon as you hear anything.
好
Okay.
好的
Great.
好 再見
Okay. Bye.
湯姆
Tom!
瑪麗
Mary?
親愛的
Hon?
你沒聽到我嗎 我很擔心
Didn't you hear me? I was worried.
你在這兒幹什麼
What are you doing in here?
我 我剛才
I, uh... I was just...
我想收拾一下史蒂文的床 萬一
I thought I'd make up Stephen's bed in case...
萬一湯姆回來
In case Tom came back.
哦
Oh.
現在幾點了
What time is it?
很晚了
It's late.
亞倫·哈特正在辦公室等你
Aaron Hart is waiting for you in the office.
這孩子一直都在不停的
I mean, the kid's been bouncing around foster homes
換領養家庭 那時沒人關心
for, like, half his life, but no one gave a shit then.
現在全鎮人都
And now suddenly the whole town's
突然開始關心了
decided it's time to give a shit.
你知道光是美國 每年就有
Do you know how many children run away
多少孩子離家出走或失蹤嗎
or go missing every year in the United States alone?
我不知道
I don't know.
你看不出這有多荒唐嗎
Don't you see how fucked up that is?
而且 這孩子死了 人人都知道
Besides, the kid's dead. Everyone knows it.
好的 亞倫 今天就談到這裏吧
Okay, Aaron, that's about all we have time for today.
隨便 好的
Whatever, sure.
非常感謝
Thanks a lot.
你爸爸要來接你嗎
Is your dad coming to get you?
嗯
Uh-huh.
青少年啊
Teenagers, huh?
怎麼樣
How's it going?
他今天恨我更多 還是恨世界更多
Does he hate me more or less than he hates the rest of the world today?
沒有 他只是不適應你們的搬家和離婚
No, he's just having a rough time with the move and the divorce.
有時我已經記不起他幾年前
Sometimes it's hard to remember he was just a cute little kid
還是個可愛的孩子
who liked to throw a ball
喜歡和爸爸一起打棒球
around with his dad a few years ago.
他現在一直很暴躁
He's so angry all the time.
他會過去的
He'll get through it.
只是個困難的年齡段
It's just a difficult age.
你聽過要來暴風雪了嗎
You hear about this storm coming in?
是的
Yeah.
如果演變成冰暴
If it turns into an ice storm,
可能會停電幾天
we could be without power for at least a couple of days.
嗯
Mmm.
你不能獨自在這裏
You probably shouldn't be up here all alone.
我和亞倫打算去鎮上的旅館
Aaron and I are thinking of moving into
住幾天等暴風雪過去
one of the hotels in town to ride it out.
呃
Uh...
如果你也去 也許我可以請你吃個飯
If we do, maybe I could take you for dinner.
我不會有事的 我們不會有事的
I'll be fine. We'll be fine.
我兒子病了 我不能帶他走動
My son, he's sick, so I can't really move him.
哦 我很遺憾
Oh. I'm sorry to hear that.
我還不知道你有個兒子 他多大了
I didn't even know you had a son. How old is he?
他18歲 史蒂文18歲
He's 18. Stephen's 18.
他是我的繼子
He's my stepson.
我還不知道
I didn't know that...
我丈夫過世了
My husband passed away, actually,
所以現在只有我和史蒂芬
so it's just Stephen and me now.
也許我們四人哪天可以一起吃個飯
Well, maybe the four of us can get dinner one day.
我們和兩個暴躁的青少年
You know, you, me and our angry teenagers.
這不合適
Look, it's not really appropriate.
亞倫是我的病人
Aaron's my patient, so...
而且他還在車上等你
And he's waiting for you in the car.
好的
Sure, okay.
呃
Uh, um...
聽著 謝謝你
Well, listen, thanks.
對不起 我
Sorry, I just...
希望你兒子能好轉
I hope your son feels better.
謝謝
Thanks.
天
Shit.
該死
Oh, shit.
沒事的
It's okay.
我感覺我要瘋了
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
瑪麗 冷靜
Mary, calm down.
聽聽你的話
Look, listen to what you're saying.
我當時在 是真實的
I was there. It was real.
你是個理性 的成年人
You're a rational adult.
世上並沒有鬼你是知道的
There's no such things as ghosts, and you know that.
天啊
Oh, God.
我覺得你經歷的是深眠狀態
I think that you experienced something known as parasomnia.
一種能引發夜驚的睡眠失調
A sleep disorder that can trigger night terrors.
可我看到了他 我看到了湯姆
I... But I saw him. I saw Tom.
人人都說他死了
Everybody's been saying he's dead,
我一直希望這不是真的 但這肯定是真的
and I kept wanting it not to be true, but it must be.
我覺得考慮到你受到的壓力
I think that with the amount of stress you're under
以及你已經有的睡眠失調
and the existence of disturbed sleep already,
這完全說得通
it makes complete sense.
說實話
And frankly,
你看到出走的孩子也能解釋
you know, the fact that you saw the runaway boy also tracks.
你一直在找他
You know, you've been looking for him,
你擔心他
you're worried about him.
這不意味著他死了
Does not mean he's dead,
更不用說變成鬼糾纏你
let alone haunting you.
你覺得你夢裏那孩子的腳步聲
Do you think that the sound of the child's footsteps
是不是因為你想起
in your dream could be a reminder of the child that
你失去的兒子
you might think you've actually lost?
讓你想起以前
You know, of the son that
你兒子害怕時就來你房裏
used to come into your room at night when he was scared.
你覺得你夢裏
Do you think that that voiceless child
那個不說話的孩子 既可能是湯姆
in your dream could be Stephen...
也可能是湯姆
...as much as it's Tom?
在車禍之前很長時間
Long before the accident,
我記得你就跟我說過
I remember you telling me that
你感覺在失去史蒂芬
you were feeling like you were losing Stephen.
在失去你的兒子
That you were losing your little boy.
你還記得嗎
Do you remember that?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我經歷了很多不幸
I had been through so much.
是啊 跟我說說那個史蒂芬
Yeah. Well, tell me about that Stephen.
車禍之前的史蒂芬
You know, Stephen before the accident.
甚至是他出現行為問題之前
Before the behavioral problems even.
有件事我從沒告訴你 那天早上
I never told you this, but that morning,
他求我別把他送走
he begged me not to send him away.
繼續
Go on.
史蒂芬一直怪在理查德身上
Stephen always blamed Richard.
不過是我找到了那所學校
But I was the one who found the school.
我不知道
I just didn't know
怎麼同時兼任他的心理醫生和母親
how to be his therapist and his mother.
瑪麗
Mary?
關於湯姆的噩夢
Look, the nightmare about Tom
可能是關於史蒂文的
may be about Stephen,
但這是因為一切都是關於史蒂
but that's because everything's about Stephen.
我想跟你談談
Look, I'd like to talk to you about prescribing
開點藥來調和你的睡眠
something to regulate your sleep, okay?
所以我要做個血液檢查
So I'm gonna need some blood work.
在此期間 你照顧好自己
In the meantime, take care of yourself.
謝謝
Thanks.
開始襲擊人類
...starts to attack humans
即使我們不是它們的天然獵物
when we're not their natural prey.
科學家們能找出辦法防止這樣的悲劇嗎
And can scientists find a way to prevent these tragic events?
嗨 對不起 我剛才 請進
Hi. Sorry, I was, uh... Come in.
這種鯊魚是海洋中最非凡的魚類
This shark is the most charismatic fish in the ocean.
大白鯊體重可以超過4-5000磅
White sharks can weigh in excess of 4 or 5,000 pounds.
體長超過20英尺
Get in excess of 20 feet long.
所以 這是一種很大的魚
So, that's a very big fish.
我們知道 這些鯊魚可以活到
We know that these sharks can live...
今天要為這位年輕人做什麼
So, what are we doing for this young man today, then?
不是為我
Actually, it's for me.
我要做個血液檢查
I just need some blood work done.
生什麼病了
What's wrong with you?
沒什麼 我沒事
Nothing, I'm fine.
那你為什麼沒去醫生那裏檢查
Then why haven't you taken yourself to the doctor?
我不想留下他一個人
I don't like to leave him alone.
我盡量少離開家
I try not to leave the house too much.
帥氣的男孩
Handsome boy.
他的眼睛像你
He's got your eyes.
他不
He's not...
謝謝
Thank you.
你一個人照顧他
You take care of him on your own?
嗯
Mmm-hmm. Hmm.
他看起來很好強壯
He looks good. Strong.
你肯定照顧得很好
You must be doing something right.
你這個年齡的女人 血壓不該這麼高
Blood pressure is too high for a woman your age.
我們能不能只是
Could we just, um...
是我多管閒事了
None of my beeswax.
我來
I get it.
你等著就是了
You just wait.
醫生拿到血檢結果之後
The doctor will tell you the same thing
也會對你這麼說的
when he gets the results.
你什麼時候送史蒂芬去
So, when are you taking Stephen in?
月底
End of the month.
威爾森醫生說我該開始練習離家了
Dr. Wilson says I need to start practicing leaving the nest.
這不算離家吧
I'm not really sure this counts.
昨天我在鎮上看到道格·哈特了
I saw Doug Hart in town yesterday.
天啊 我那天對他很不客氣
Oh, my God, I was so rude to him.
有意思
Funny.
他還覺得惹你生氣了
He thought he'd offended you.
你該給他打電話
You should call him.
跟他約會
Ask him out.
也許我只是打電話跟他道個歉
Maybe I should call him just to apologize.
是啊 道歉
Yeah, to apologize.
那天我很不應該
I felt like such an ass the other day.
我不知情
I had no idea.
露西把情況都跟我說了
Lucy explained everything to me.
她肯定的
Oh, of course she did.
你一個人照顧他肯定很艱難
That must have been hard, taking care of him by yourself.
這也是她跟你說的
She told you about that, too?
是的 史蒂芬
And yes, Stephen...
我要把他送到一個護理中心
I'm moving him to a care home.
對不起 我不知道 她沒告訴我這個
Oh, I'm sorry, I had no idea. She didn't tell me that.
我以為
I thought...
對不起 我
I'm sorry. I...
我都不會說話了
You know, I... This is hard. I haven't...
很久沒跟男人一起吃飯了
I haven't done this in a while.
車禍之前你們很親近
Were you guys close before the accident?
非常親近
Very.
我和理查德結婚時他五歲
He was five when Richard and I got married.
他對我比對他爸爸更親近
He was closer to me than his dad.
但後來他到了青春期
But then he hit puberty,
就像家裏有了個陌生人
and it was like I had a stranger in the house.
我家的亞倫也是
Yeah, Aaron, too. I'm just like,
就像完全換了個人
he's a completely different species.
亞倫是個好孩子
Aaron is a good kid.
他的老師們不這麼認為
Well, his teachers disagree.
我上周去見了校長
I had a meeting with the principal last week.
黑斯廷斯校長 他很差勁
Principal Hastings? He's the worst!
史蒂文也在那裏上過學
So, Stephen went there, too.
但後來被開除了
Until he was expelled.
不會吧 為什麼
No! What for?
是學校小題大做了
Mmm, the whole thing was totally blown out of proportion.
幾個學生在游泳池裏打鬧
There were some kids, and they were messing around in the pool.
他們可能只是戲弄史蒂文
And I guess they were just teasing Stephen.
有一天他報復了但沒傷到任何人
One day he retaliated, but no one got hurt.
他生母去世後 他經歷了很多痛苦
After his mom died, he was dealing with a lot of grief.
等他進入青春期 幾乎不跟任何人說話
And by the time he was a teenager, he barely spoke to anyone
只除了我 後來就出了
except me, and then it was, you know...
我感覺亞倫跟任何人都說話 只除了我
I feel like Aaron talks to everyone but me.
對我完全不理不睬
He just completely shuts me out.
嗯
Hmm.
我想我就不打擾你們休息了
Well, I guess I should let you two get to bed.
不早了
It's getting late.
史蒂芬
Stephen?
我說過了 肯定發生了什麼
I told you, something's going on,
不只是我的幻覺
and it's not just in my head.
瑪麗 深呼吸
Mary, take a deep breath
然後想想你說的話
and think about what you're saying.
請聽我說
Please just listen to me.
我以為是個夢 但不是
I thought it was a dream, but it wasn't.
我當時醒著
I was awake and...
是深眠狀態
Well, sleep parasomnia...
不是什麼深眠狀態 好嗎
It's not fucking sleep parasomnia, okay?
拜託 你一定要相信我
Please, you have to believe me.
聽聽你的話 你在談鬼
And listen to what you're saying. You're talking about ghosts!
這不是你
This isn't you.
真是的 難道我不知道這聽起來很荒唐嗎
For God's sake, don't you think I know how this sounds?
肯定發生了什麼  我能證明
Something is happening. I can prove it.
史蒂文的臉上有抓痕
Stephen, he has scratches on his face.
你睡眠不足
You are sleep deprived.
頭腦不清
You're confused.
你想搞明白一切
You're struggling to make sense of everything
然後得出了一些荒謬的解釋
and latching onto irrational explanations.
聽著 也許是你不小心抓了他的臉
Look, maybe you scratched him yourself by accident.
什麼
What?
天啊
Oh, God.
我不知道哪個更糟
I don't know what's worse.
要麼這些都是真事 要麼是我瘋了
Either this really is happening, or I'm losing my mind.
我經常聽到牆裏
I keep hearing these weird noises
和地板下有奇怪的聲音
in the walls and under the floor.
瑪麗 我是來幫你的
Mary, I am here to help.
我會催促他們盡快完成你的血檢
Listen, I'm gonna rush the lab for your blood work,
然後就可以 給你開些抗抑鬱藥
and then I think we should get you straight onto an anti-depressant.
幾小時後我們再聊 好嗎
I'll talk to you in a few hours, okay?
好
Okay.
現在是即時新聞
Now, to some breaking news
關於兒童福利機構幾天前報告的
concerning the young deaf boy reported missing several days ago
失蹤聾啞兒童
by Social Services.
不到一小時前
Within the past hour,
有人在佛羅里達州哈索恩的一個公園
a boy fitting the description of 9-year-old Tom Patterson
看到了和9歲的
has been spotted
湯姆·帕特森特徵相符的男孩
in a park in Hawthorne, Florida.
接到一個當地居民的報警之後
Acting on a call from a local resident,
哈索恩警方正在這一地區進行大規模搜索
Hawthorne police are now conducting a wide search of the area.
他們懷疑他可能是乘坐長途汽車來這裏
They speculate he may have traveled by Greyhound bus,
但現在還不知道 他具體在哪兒
but as yet are still to determine his exact whereabouts.
稍後是即將到來的 暴風雪的報道
We'll be back after the break with more on the winter storm heading our way.
只有我
Only me!
嗨
Hey!
我知道你說過什麼都不需要 不過
Okay, I know you said that you didn't need anything, but...
我也不是第一次了 露西
It's hardly my first rodeo, Luce.
你今晚真的不和我們一起嗎
Um... Sure you don't want to stay with us tonight?
不 我們沒事
No, we're fine.
我剛才還以為
For a moment there, I thought I was...
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
是的 沒什麼
Yeah, it's nothing.
我只是一直沒睡好
I just haven't been sleeping that well.
你真的什麼都不缺了嗎
Um, sure you have everything?
燈籠 毛毯
Lanterns? Blankets?
足夠的木柴
Enough wood?
是的 謝謝你
Yes, thank you.
好 你保重
Okay, take care, all right?
好的 你也是
Yeah, you, too.
好 再見
Yeah. Bye.
再見
Bye.
燈籠
Lanterns...
天啊
Oh, God...
是我
It's just me.
你嚇了我一跳
You scared me.
對不起闖了進來 我敲過門 但沒人應答
Sorry to barge in. I tried knocking, but no one answered.
我沒聽到你的車
I didn't hear your car.
有一輛鏟雪車 擋住了你家的車道
Yeah, that plow just came. Your drive's blocked.
我只能把車停在路邊走了過來
I had to park down the road and walk in.
哦 好的
Oh. Okay.
我來是為了感謝
I just came to say thank you
昨晚的款待 也來看看你還好嗎
for last night and see if you're okay.
我和亞倫在"假日旅館"訂了個房間
Aaron and I did end up getting a suite down at the Holiday Inn,
你們真的不跟我們一起去嗎
so, you're sure you guys don't want to come with us?
不 你太客氣了
No, that's kind of you.
我們經歷過更糟的天氣
We've weathered worse.
我昨晚很開心
I had a great time last night.
我也是
Me, too.
呃
Um...
他們找到了湯姆 我真是無比的欣慰
I can't tell you what a relief it is they found Tom.
那個離家出走的孩子
You know, the runaway kid.
是啊 是啊 佛羅里達州
Yeah, yeah, Florida.
但後來發現不是他
That turned out to be a false alarm.
你沒聽說嗎
You didn't hear?
沒有
No.
相信他會出現的
I mean, I'm sure he's gonna turn up.
可能會在附近的某個鎮上發現他
They'll probably find him two towns over.
越向北就越
...a little bit as you head further up to the north.
不管你怎麼看
No matter how you look at it though,
這都是一次嚴重的冬季風暴
we're talking about a major winter storm...
你不要緊吧
You okay?
呃
Uh...
我還有很多事要做
I have a lot to do.
我就不送你了
You don't mind letting yourself out.
好的
Sure.
道格 我
Doug! I'm...
你好 威爾森醫生 抱歉 我剛才在樓下
Hi, Dr. Wilson. Sorry, I was downstairs.
瑪麗
Mary?
是的
Yeah.
我剛拿到了你的血檢結果
I have just gotten your blood work back from the lab.
好
Okay.
說實話 我有些失望
Frankly, I'm a little disappointed.
什麼
What?
如果你告訴我你在自行用藥
If you'd have told me you were self-medicating,
我們就能避免很多誤會了
we could have avoided a lot of confusion here.
鑒於你吃了那麼多藥
It's no wonder you're having so many problems,
難怪你出了那麼多問題
given the amount of pills you're taking.
你什麼意思
What are you talking about?
瑪麗 苯二氮平類藥物不是能隨便吃的
Mary, benzodiazepines are not a class of drugs we mess around with.
我什麼都沒吃
I'm not taking anything.
除了混合用藥有可能會致命之外
Aside from the fact that mixing prescription drugs can be lethal...
混合
Mixing?
我只能估計你在吃史蒂芬的藥
I can only assume that you are taking medication from Stephen,
這不光威脅到你的健康
which not only puts your health at risk,
還有他的健康
but his also.
我沒聽我說 我不懂你什麼意思
You're not listening to me. I don't know what you're talking about.
我什麼藥都沒吃
I haven't taken anything.
我本來很願意給你開些有助於睡眠的藥
I would have happily prescribed you something to help you sleep.
雖然藥效會溫和一些
It would have been less potent,
但我肯定會的
but of course I would have done it.
你搞錯了 這不是我的血檢結果
You've made a mistake, those are not my results.
對不起 我現在不方便
I'm sorry, I really can't talk right now.
我回頭再聯繫你
I'm gonna have to call you back.
瑪麗
Mary.
Mary!
瑪麗 瑪麗
Mary? Mary?
你撥打的電話無法接通
The number you are trying to call is not reachable.
史蒂芬 史蒂芬
Stephen. Stephen...
不 住手
No! Stop!
安靜 小寶貝
Hush little baby
別說話
Don't say a word
媽媽會給你買一隻模仿鳥
Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird
如果這只模仿鳥
And if that mockingbird
媽媽會給你買個
Mama's gonna buy you a...
別怕 別怕 別怕
It's okay, it's okay. It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
別怕 我在
Hey. It's okay. I'm here.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no, no! No!
別怕 對不起 對不起
It's okay. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
看著我 我是你兒子 史蒂芬
Look. Look at me. It's your son, Stephen.
別怕 我要把它揭下來
It's okay. I'm gonna take this off.
好
Okay.
對不起 好
I'm sorry. Okay.
安靜 不 噓
Hush, no! Shh!
別喊
Don't scream!
別怕 喂 喂
It's okay. Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
別怕
It's okay.
這是怎麼回事 拜託
What's happening? Please.
我在照顧你
I'm taking care of you,
就像你照顧我
just like you take care of me.
我在做夢嗎
Am I dreaming?
不是
No.
不再是了
Not anymore.
我不明白
I don't understand.
這
Is... And...
車禍一周後
When I woke up in the hospital,
當我在醫院醒來
a week after the accident,
你在我身邊
you were by my side,
伺候我的一切
waiting on my every need.
可你不動 你不說話
But you didn't move. You didn't speak.
是的
No.
你們都以為我不能
And you all assumed I couldn't.
我只是不希望這一切結束
I just didn't want it to end.
我越是什麼都不干 這事就越輕鬆
And the longer I did nothing, the easier it got.
醫生一直對你說
The doctors kept telling you
現代醫學對大腦的瞭解有多麼少
how little is known about the brain.
我那時不明白
I couldn't understand.
你的大腦掃瞄一直在改善
Your scans kept improving.
你的反射也正常
Your reflexes were normal.
你只是看到了你想看到的
You saw what you wanted to see.
這幾個月我們在一起那麼幸福
These last few months, we've been so happy together.
只有你和我
Just you and me,
直到他來了
until he came here.
湯姆
Tom.
我不能放他走
I couldn't let him go.
他看到了我
He'd seen me.
你殺了他
You killed him.
我是你兒子
I'm your son!
I'm your son.
你為什麼總是更關心他們
Why did you always pick them over me?
我比不上他們了
I won't compete anymore.
不 沒事的 噓
Hey, no, no. It's okay. Shh.
聽著 喂 喂
Hey, look, hey, hey, hey, hey.
沒事的
It's okay.
他不是鬼
He's not a ghost.
他就在樓下
He's downstairs.
我本打算殺了他 可他爬進了管道間裏
I was gonna deal with him, but he climbed into the crawlspace.
到我房間的就是他
That was him in my room.
嗯
Uh-huh.
我以為都過去了
Yeah, I thought it was all over.
但我低估了這藥
But I underestimated these.
他還活著
He's alive.
我把他堵在裏面
I blocked him in.
等著他餓死
I was waiting for him to starve.
他的那個聲音
That sound of him.
他在黑暗中刮擦的聲音
That sound of him scratching around in the dark.
以前在你的茶裏放一粒
You know, one in your tea used
就能讓你安睡一整夜
to put you down all night.
自從他來了之後 我不得不加大了劑量
I had to up the dosage since he's been here.
喂 過來 過來
Hey, come here, come here.
張開嘴
Open your mouth.
拜託
Please.
張開
Open.
不不
No, no...
啊
Ow!
停下 停下
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
嚥下去
Swallow.
乖
Good girl.
等你醒來時 他就不在了
When you wake up, he'll be gone.
我們就能回到正常
We can go back to normal.
只有你和我 我保證
Just you and me. I promise.
喂
Hello?
不別再讓我等
No! No, do not put me on hold again.
我需要你們派人去找瑪麗·波特曼
I need you to send someone out to see Mary Portman.
在德爾福路28號
At 28 Delphi Lane.
不 她
No. She...
不 她沒出事故
No, she has not been in an accident.
我覺得她被下藥了
I think she's being drugged.
你已到達目的地
You have reached your destination.
什麼
What?
該死
Shit.
天啊
Oh, God...
安靜
Shut up!
我以為你會開心
I thought you'd be happy.
現在你不必把我送走了
Now you don't have to send me away.
我只想幫你 史蒂芬
I just want to help you, Stephen.
你出了嚴重的車禍
You were in a terrible accident.
身體不好
You're not well.
我聽見你說了
I heard you
在昨晚
last night.
你又要把我送走
You're trying to send me away again.
因為他
Because of him!
不 不是因為他
No, no, it's not because of him.
你把我的房間給了他
You gave him my room.
你要替換我
You're replacing me!
沒人能取代你
No one could ever replace you.
我保證
I promise.
拜託 把斧子放下
Please, just put the ax down,
我們可以談談
and we can talk about this.
我能解決此事
I can fix this.
我們可以回到以前的樣子
We can go back to how it was.
我還可以請人幫你
And I can get you some help, okay?
拜託 把斧子放下
Please, just put the ax down.
槍裏沒有子彈
It's not loaded.
我這是為了我們
I'm doing this for us!
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
我要帶你離開這裏
I'm gonna get you out of here.
不
No!
快跑
Run!
史蒂芬 拜託 住手
Stephen, please, stop!
別說了 你要毀了一切
Stop it! Stop it! You're ruining everything.
冷靜
Calm down.
我是在幫你收拾殘局
I am trying to fix your mess.
史蒂芬 這不是你
Stephen, this isn't you.
閉嘴 你閉嘴 你不瞭解我
Shut up. Just shut up. You don't know me.
你是個好孩子史蒂芬
You're a good boy, Stephen.
不
No.
只是因為車禍
It was just the accident.
那不是意外車禍
It wasn't an accident!
我不在乎自己的死活 只要能撞死他
I didn't care if I died as long as he did.
你是我的一切
You're what I... You...
你要把我送走
You were sending me away.
我必須阻止他
I had to stop him.
不能讓他帶我離開你
I couldn't let him take me away from you.
別碰我
Don't touch me.
我寧願死 也不想離開你
I would rather die than be away from you.
噓
Shh...
我們不需要別人
We don't need anyone else.
天啊 湯姆
Oh, God. Tom!
不
No!
天啊 你在哪兒
Oh, God. Where are you?
湯姆
Oh, Tom.
湯姆 來
Tom, come.
下來 來
Come down. Come.
跟我來 快
Come with me. Quick!
安靜 小寶貝
Hush little baby
別說話
Don't say a word
媽媽會給你買一隻模仿鳥
Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird
如果這只模仿年不唱歌
And if that mockingbird won't sing
瑪麗
Mary?
我是威爾森醫生 你
It's Dr. Wilson, are you...
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
瑪麗
Mary?
家裏有人嗎
Anybody home?
你們都好吧
Everybody okay?
我覺得
I just thought we'd, uh,
在警察來之前我們該聊聊
have a little chat before the police get here.
天啊
Oh, God.
我覺得我們沒時間
I don't really think that we have time for...
沒時間胡鬧 是不是
For games right now, do we?
史蒂芬 我是威爾森醫生
Stephen, it's Dr. Wilson.
蒂芬
Stephen?
你勸她送走我
You told her to get rid of me.
可她愛我
But she loves me.
沒人能分開我們
And no one is gonna keep us apart.
湯姆 沒事 他走了
Tom. It's okay, he's gone.
沒事
It's okay.
給 穿上
Here. Put this on.
他來了
He's coming.
天啊
Oh, God.
你留在這裏
You stay here.
我會回來找你的
I'm coming back for you.
天啊 道格
Oh, God, Doug!
快 跟我來
Quick, come with me.
等等
Wait...
在這兒等著 等等
Wait here. Wait.
威爾森醫生
Dr. Wilson...
對不起
I'm sorry.
沒事的 我會帶你離開這裏
It's okay. I'm gonna get you out of here.
他在這裏
He was here...
一直都在
The whole time.
真對不起
I'm so sorry.
在史蒂芬的腦子裏
In Stephen's mind...
不要去反駁他的錯覺
Don't challenge his delusions.
知道嗎
You understand?
別讓他看到那孩子
Don't let him see the boy.
他要的是你 只有你
It's you he wants, only you.
進入他的錯覺中
Enter his delusions...
沒事的 我幫你
It's okay, I get you.
不帶那孩子走
No. Get the boy out.
天啊
Oh, God!
Oh, God.
留在這裏
Stay here.
沒事的
It's okay.
不
No!
住手 住手 拜託
Stop! Stop! Please!
不 別掙扎
No, stop it!
不 聽我說
No, listen to me.
住手聽我說
Stop. Listen to me.
不不
No! No!
冷靜 冷靜
Calm down, calm down.
你說的對
You were right, okay?
我專注於我的病人
I was focused on my patients,
沒能考慮到你
when I should have been thinking about you.
不已經太晚了
No! No, too late!
等等住手
Wait! Stop!
我不知道
I didn't know.
不明白你這麼做是為了我們
I didn't understand that you were doing it for us.
我不知道
I didn't know.
為了我們能在一起
So that we could be together.
不 你撒謊 你在幫他
No. You liar! You're helping him.
不我趕走了他
No, I got rid of him.
不
No.
是的 他現在走了
I did! He's gone now.
現在只有你和我 我保證
It's just you and me, I promise!
這是我們的房子
This is our house.
不
No.
你說的對
You were right.
他不該在這裏
He shouldn't be here.
是我糊塗
I was confused.
我以為失去了你
I thought I'd lost you.
可現在你在這裏
But now you're here.
我怎麼可能替換你
How could I ever replace you?
我愛你 史蒂芬
I love you, Stephen.
這裏就是你的歸宿
This is where you belong.
你
You!
天啊
Oh, God.
湯姆
Tom.
那裏沒有路 快
There's no way down from there. Quick!
我接著你
I got you.
好的
That's it.
好 我們走 我們走 快
Okay, let's go. Let's go. Quick.
我們走
Let's go.
湯姆
Tom!
快跑 湯姆
Run, Tom!
走
Go!
史蒂芬 不
Stephen, no!
拜託
Please!
請不要
Please, no.
讓開
Move.
不
No!
湯姆 湯姆
Tom! Tom!
我接著你 我接著你
I got you. I got you.
我
I got...
你準備好這麼做了嗎
Are you ready to do this?
是的
Yup, I am.
我和他都是
We both are.
會為你們辦好手續的
The papers will be waiting for you.
謝謝你 瓊
Thanks, Joan.
他是個幸運的孩子
He's a lucky kid.
我能看看嗎
Can I see?
畫的很好
It's good.
你想養條狗
You want a dog?
可能
Maybe.
會很好的
It's gonna be good.
如果這只模仿鳥不唱歌
And if that mockingbird don't sing
媽媽會給你買個鑽戒
Mama's gonna buy you a diamond ring
安靜小寶貝別說話
Hush, little baby, don't say a word
媽媽會給你買一隻模仿鳥
Mama's gonna buy you a mockingbird